Guide to the Martin Bronfenbrenner Papers, 1939-1995 and undated RL.00153
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Teaching Material Series, 1949-1996, 5 boxes
  Consists chiefly of lecture notes, examination papers, and course syllabi covering subjects that Bronfenbrenner taught through classes and seminars at Carnegie-Mellon, Duke and in Japan, including microeconomics, macroeconomics, income distribution, international economics, trade, Japanese history and the Japanese economy. Box 27 is dedicated to correspondence between Bronfenbrenner and his graduate students.
  - Teaching files (Box 23-27)
- Oversize Material, 1950-1969 and undated, 1 folder
  Clippings, newspapers, and other items from the Research Series, Heterodox and Japan subseries. A group of six Japanese campus newspapers contain front-page articles in the English language on 1969 student unrest and violence on Japanese campuses.
  - Daily Cardinal, Univ. of Wisconsin/Madison, article by Bronfenbrenner on Japanese university system, 1950 Oct. 7 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Clipping, article by Bronfenbrenner on Japanese students in U.S., 1950 Dec. (Oversize-folder 1)
  - McCarthy's Rise in Wisconsin, The Hindu, Madras, article by Bronfenbrenner, 1953 Sept. 21 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - The Mita Campus, Tokyo, Japan [English], campus newspapers, 1957 Apr.-1969 Nov., 7 issues (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Clipping from Carnegie-Mellon campus newspapers, article by Bronfenbrenner on student unrest, 1969 Sept. 19 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Small color poster, Japanese, with images of 16 political and social scientists, including Bronfenbrenner, circa 1960s (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Statistical estimates of liquidity functions in the U.S., undated (Oversize-folder 1)